

I am an experienced front end engineer with a focus on writing JavaScript applications for the web and mobile. A strong advocate for code collaboration and agile best practices, I thrive in a team environment where I can lead, learn, mentor, and have a good fun time.

CONTACT

617.319.0052

iabram617@gmail.com

≥ iabram617@gmail.com

Watertown MA

in LinkedIn @jaimeabramson

GitHub @jabram

EDUCATION

Certificate in Web Development

Center for Digital Imaging Arts Waltham MA May 2011

Bachelor's Degree

Film Production Boston University May 2003

SKILLS

- ReactJS
- React Native
- Front end web development (HTML/CSS)
- Storybook / design system implementation
- JavaScript testing
- Gitflow best practices and code reviews
- Pair programming
- Technical strategy / Strategic planning
- Agile / Scrum ceremonies
- Task estimations
- Team collaboration

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance Software Developer | September 2022 - present

- Currently working with a music festival to maintain and upgrade their React Native mobile application and NodeJS admin website
- Implemented front end best practices and trained a team on organizing a complex ReactJS web application

CANTINA CONSULTING, Boston MA

Senior Engineer | May 2021 - August 2022

- Performed as the technical and project lead for a team that revamped a set of legacy React Native mobile applications for 2022, improving their functionality and eliminating years of regression bugs
- Led an engineering team discussion on technical strategy in 2022, ensuring alignment with overall business goals
- Fostered a collaborative and inclusive team environment by encouraging open discussion and providing support to other team members

Engineer | September 2018 - May 2021

- Led a front end team in defining and building a ReactJS web application for creating complex AR audio experiences based on wearable gestures and location data; showcased work at SXSW 2019
- Successfully launched a React Native mobile application for managing COVID-19 protocols on movie and television sets, delivering it within a tight deadline in 2020
- Demonstrated adaptability by routinely learning new technologies and expanding skill set in order to add immediate value to client projects

Associate Engineer | February 2015 - September 2018

- Collaborated closely with product owners and designers to create accessible interfaces using consistent UI patterns; often traveling to client sites to be embedded within their teams
- Advocated to set projects of for success by breaking down work in to clear and manageable tasks that can be easily estimated and measured
- Participated in internal initiatives outside core role from assisting with video production to leading a research and analysis project

OVERDRIVE INTERACTIVE, Allston MA

Web Developer | August 2011 - February 2015

- Built client projects as a full stack solo developer utilizing the MAMP stack
- Advocated for collaboration across teams during all phases of work in an effort to quickly surface unknowns
- Built applications on social platforms to engage audiences
- Worked with SEO specialists to collect and track analytics